Lestoque, Albert; Papers ger059
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Family and general correspondence files, 1914-1960; 5; 103 file folders
  - General correspondence with individuals, 1932-1960; 5.2
    - Sheldon, Eva S., 1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 66)
    - Schoenstedt, Walter, 1939 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 67)
    - Simon, Shephard, 1951 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 68)
    - Somin, Willy O. (Wallis O. Stahl), 1938-1940 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 69)
    - Stahl, Walter, 1938 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 70)
    - Staudinger, Else, 1940; 1943 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 71)
    - Steel, Johannes (The Insider), 1939 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 72)
    - Strohschnitter, Lydia, 1948-1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 73)
    - Vansittart, Lord, 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 74)
    - Waite, John B., 1946 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 75)
    - Walter, Gerda, 1947-1955 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 76)
  - Correspondence with organizations, newspapers, publishers, etc., 1914-1958; 5.3
    - American Association for the United Nations, Inc., 1946; Undated (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 77)
    - Aufbau (signed Graf), 1943 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 78)
    - The Authors' Guild / The Authors' League of America, 1939 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 79)
    - The Christian Science Monitor, 1958 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 80)
    - Citizens for Victory, 1943-1944 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 81)
    - The City Club of Denver, 1946-1948 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 82)
    - The Denver Art Museum, 1946-1947 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 83)
    - The Denver Club, 1945-1946 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 84)
    - Denver Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1944 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 85)
    - Denver Country Club, 1946-1947 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 86)
    - Denver Post, 1951; 1956 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 87)
    - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists (Albert Einstein), 1947 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 88)
    - Feuer. Monatsschrift für Kunst und künstlerische Kultur, 1920 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 89)
    - Frankfurter Zeitung, 1914 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 90)
    - German-American Writers Association (GAWA), 1938-1940; clippings (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 91)
    - Institute of International Education, 1952 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 92)
    - International Committee for the Study of European Questions, 1937; 1947-1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 93)
    - National America Denmark Association, 1943 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 94)
    - Neue Juristische Wochenschrift, 1958 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 95)
    - Office of Strategic Services, 1942-1944 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 96)
    - Rechtsprechung zum Wiedergutmachungsrecht, 1958 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 97)
    - Universität Köln, 1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 98)
    - University of Denver, 1945-1947 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 99)
    - War Production Board, Conservation Division, 1942 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 100)
    - The Writers Special Service, 1939 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 101)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1937-1949 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 102)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1951-1957 (Box 6 (5-Family and general correspondence files), Folder 103)
- Correspondence and materials dealing with German properties and possessions, 1928-1943; 6; 41 file folders
  This series contains correspondence files which document Lestoque's dealings in regard to the Leser family properties in Germany. A large section of this series is comprised of the case files of attorney Robert Mand, Lestoque's legal representative in Germany, 1939-1943, who was responsible for dealing with the dissolution of the Leser family possessions after family members were forced to flee.
  - Blatzheim, Hans, 1938 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 1)
  - Bürgermeisteramt Godesberg, 1928 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 2)
  - H. Delliehausen, 1938 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 3)
  - Deutsche Effecten- und Wechselbank, 1934-1940 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 4)
  - Endemann, Harald, 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 5)
  - Esser, A. J., 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 6)
  - Finanzamt Bonn, 1932-1933 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 7)
  - Haensel, Carl, 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 8)
  - Haensel, Carl, 1938 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 9)
  - Harrison, Richard & Margaret (porcelain storage), 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 10)
  - Hoku Kunstgewerbliche Werkstätten, 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 11)
  - Mose-Andersen, Anneliese, 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 12)
  - Herbert Oppenheimer, Nathan, Vandyk & Mackay, 1934-1939 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 13)
  - Pachtverträge mit der Gartenbauschule, 1928 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 14)
  - Preußische Steuern (Prussian taxes), 1933-1936 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 15)
  - Reichsfinanzhof, Köln, 1934-1939 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 16)
  - Reichsfluchtsteuerbescheid (Reichs Flight Tax Assessment), 1934-1940 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 17)
  - Rohde, Albert (Gartenarchitekt), 1935-1947 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 18)
  - Stadtkasse Bad Godesberg, 1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 19)
  - Tönergasse 6, Frankfurt am Main, property, 1936-1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 20)
  - Walter, Paul I., 1934-1937 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 21)
  - Wassermeyer, Wolf, 1938-1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 22)
  - Files pertaining to the "Konkurssache Dr. Albert Israel Leser", from the records of German lawyer, Robert Mand, 1939-1943; 6.23
    - Konkurssache Dr. Albert Israel Leser -- Decision, 1941 April 30 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 23)
    - Aktenverzeichnis, Undated (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 24)
    - Konkurssache, Band 1 (Hauptakten), 1939-1943 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 25)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 3 (Gläubiger), 1939-1942 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 26)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 4 (Steuern), 1939-1942 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 27)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 5 (Briefwechsel mit Gemeinschuldner), 1939-1940 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 28)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 6 (Briefwechsel mit Geschwister Leser), 1939-1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 29)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 7 (Grundstücke), 1939-1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 30)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 8 (Kaufvertrag Stadt Godesberg), 1939-1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 31)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 9 (Kaufvertrag Blatzheim u.a), 1939-1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 32)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 10 (Kaufvertrag Scheibler), 1939-1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 33)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 11 (Mobilarvermögen), 1941 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 34)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 12 (Haus Tönesgasse 6), 1941-1942 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 35)
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 13 (Kasse), 1939-1942 (Box 7 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 36)
  - Files pertaining to the "Konkurssache Dr. Albert Israel Leser", from the records of German lawyer, Robert Mand, 1939-1943; 6.24
    - Konkurssache Leser, Band 14 (Rheinisches Heim), 1940-1941 (Box 8 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 1)
    - Konkurssache Leser (Vermögensbeschlagnahme Paul Leser), 1940-1941 (Box 8 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 2)
    - Konkurssache Leser (Vermögensbeschlagnahme Frau Lingemann), 1941-1942 (Box 8 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 3)
    - Nachlasspflegeschaftssache Leser (Heinrich Lingemann / Wolf Wassermeyer), 1938-1941 (Box 8 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 4)
    - Receipts for expenditures, Heinrich Lingemann, 1939-1941 (Box 8 (6-Correspondence and materials dealing with German p), Folder 5)
- American activities, 1943-1951; 7; 9 file folders
  This series contains folders pertaining to Lestoque's activities in Denver, Colorado and include his association with the Alliance Française Denver, France Forever, the P. T. A. of the Denver Public School system, as well as with various social groups in Denver.
  - Alliance Française Denver. Notes, Undated (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 6)
  - Alliance Française Denver. Clippings, 1943-1944 (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 7)
  - Alliance Française Denver. Speeches and addresses given by Lestoque, 1947-1951; Undated (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 8)
  - Alliance Française Denver. Correspondence, 1947 (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 9)
  - Alliance Française Denver. Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 10)
  - Alliance Française Denver. Miscellaneous publications, Undated (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 11)
  - Fighting French Relief Committee, Inc. (France Forever), 1943 (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 12)
  - Denver Public Schools P.T.A., 1944-1947 (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 13)
    Correspondence, records, photo.
  - Denver Society personalities. Clippings, 1944 (Box 8 (7-American activities), Folder 14)
- Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files, 1947-1960; 8; 230 file folders
  This series is the largest series in the collection. It is noteworthy because it represents a nearly complete record of the legal battles of Albert Lestoque and other members of his family in their attempts to file restitution claims for losses incurred as a result of the Nazi takeover of their properties in Germany after 1933. The files in Series 6 document Lestoque's early efforts to maintain his family's properties after he and other family members were forced to flee from Germany, whereas the files in Series 8 deal directly with Restitution (post-1945, Wiedergutmachung) claims.
  The series is divided into three sections: the first section contains alphabetical correspondence files with individuals, legal representatives and agencies in Germany; the second section is arranged according to various legal case files, including those against the German Reich as well as ones against individual citizens and other agencies; the final section contains correspondence with occupation agencies and U.S. political figures, as well as clipping files on post-war Germany and restitution issues.
  - General correspondence files, Undated; 8.1
    - Ausgleichamt (notification of war damages), 1953-1958 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - B. P. Benzin- und Petroleumsgesellschaft, 1954 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Bank Deutscher Länder, 1955 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Banse, Werner, 1955 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Banse, Werner, 1956 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - Basler Feuer Versicherungsgesellschaft, 1947-1961 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Baum, Paulin (Notar), 1951-1952 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 21)
    - Becker, Ingeborg, 1954-1956 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 22)
    - Beuerlen, Ministerialrat, 1952 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 23)
    - Der Bezirksbeauftragte für gesperrte Vermögen beim Finanzminister des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1951-1959 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 24)
    - Blachstein, Peter, 1953 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 25)
    - Borstelmann, H., 1952 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 26)
    - Boesebeck, Ernst, 1952-1956 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 27)
    - Der Bundesministerium für Ernährung, Landwirtschaft und Forsten, 1960 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 28)
    - Einwohnermeldeamt Bad Godesberg am Rhein, 1953 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 29)
    - Finanzamt Bonn, 1952-1955 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 30)
    - Finanzamt Bonn, 1956-1961 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 31)
    - Finanzminister des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1955-1956 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 32)
    - Frankfurter Siedlungsgesellschaft, 1954 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 33)
    - Galleski, Werner, 1948 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 34)
    - Gemeinnützige Aktiengesellschaft für Angestellten-Heimstätten (GAGFAH), 1953-1954 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 35)
    - Gemeinnützige Siedlungsgesellschaft des Hilfswerks der Evangelischen Kirchen in Deutschland m.b.H., 1951-1960 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 36)
    - German Consulate General, 1951-1956 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 37)
    - Gerschel, Alfred, 1951-1952 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 38)
    - Greve, Otto-Heinrich, 1953 (Box 8 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 39)
    - Günster, Josef, 1953; 1955 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 1)
    - Gulmann, O. C. / Kaaring, Joergen, 1954-1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 2)
    - Haensel, Carl, 1952-1955 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 3)
    - Hecking, Joseph Franz, 1950 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 4)
    - Hilger, Eduard, 1947-1949 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 5)
    - Hilger, Eduard, 1950 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 6)
    - Hilger, Eduard, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 7)
    - Hilger, Eduard, 1952 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 8)
    - Hilger, Eduard, 1953 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 9)
    - Hilger, Eduard, 1954-1960 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 10)
    - Institut für Restitutionsfragen / United Restitution Office, 1952-1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 11)
    - Kofferath, Günter, 1955-1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 12)
    - Kofferath, Günter, 1958-1965 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 13)
    - Der Kreisbeauftragte für gesperrte Vermögen, 1951-1952 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 14)
    - Kriegssparkasse, Bad Godesberg, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - Kriminalpolizei, Bad Godesberg, 1957-1960 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Kubuschok, Egon, 1950-1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Kuboschok, Egon, 1952-1953 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1951-1953 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1955 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 21)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 22)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1957-1958 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 23)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1959-1960 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 24)
    - Küsel-Meise, Agnes, 1963 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 25)
    - Landeszentralbank Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 26)
    - Mietverträge (Rental agreements), Undated (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 27)
    - Rental agreement, Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1952-1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 28)
    - Rental agreement, E. Burkart Immobilen, 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 29)
    - Rental agreement, Hermann Menkoff, 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 30)
    - Rental agreement, Notgemeinschaft der deutschen Wissenschaft, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 31)
    - Rental agreement, Pädagogium Godesberg Otto Kühne Schule, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 32)
    - Rental agreement, Tomberg & Co., Köln, 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 33)
    - Rental agreement, Westdeutsche Immobilien-Verwertung, 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 34)
    - Rental agreement, Westdeutscher Verein zur Förderung der Christengemeinschaft, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 35)
    - Property owners, 1950 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 36)
    - Ministerpräsident des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 37)
    - Mundorf, Heinrich, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 38)
    - Oberfinanzpräsident Köln, 1951; 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 39)
    - Oberstes Rückerstattungsgericht Zweiter Senat / Supreme Restitution Court, Second Division, 1955; 1960 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 40)
    - Rheinisch-Westfälische Bank, 1952-1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 41)
    - Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität Bonn, 1946-1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 42)
    - Schugt, Peter, 1957 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 43)
    - Schulte-Wolff, Marga, 1951-1957 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 44)
    - Sommer, Wilhelm, 1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 45)
    - Stadtverwaltung der Stadt Godesberg, 1952 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 46)
    - Stein, Erich, 1938; 1954 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 47)
    - Steinhoff, Fritz (Ministerpräsident), 1956 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 48)
    - Strömsdörfer, 1956-1960 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 49)
    - Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes, 1951 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 50)
    - Team Werbeagentur, 1959 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 51)
    - United States Court of Restitution Appeals of the Allied High Commission for Germany, 1951-1953 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 52)
    - Walraf, Josef, 1951-1952 (Box 9 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 53)
    - Walraf, Josef, 1953 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 1)
    - Walraf, Josef, 1954 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 2)
    - Walraf, Josef, 1955-1956 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 3)
    - Warland, Gerichtsassessor, 1954 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 4)
    - Wassermeyer, Wolf, 1948-1957 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 5)
    - Werner, Ernst, 1951 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 6)
    - Westdeutschen Verein zur Förderung der Christengemeinschaft, 1951; 1954 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 7)
    - Wiedergutmachungskammer des Landgerichts Bonn, 1950-1952 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 8)
    - Wiedergutmachungskammer des Landgerichts Bonn, 1953-1954 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 9)
    - Wiedergutmachungskammer des Landgerichts Bonn, 1955-1957 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 10)
    - Wiedergutmachungskammer des Landgerichts Bonn, 1960-1961 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 11)
    - Zentralamt für Vermögensverwaltung, British Zone, 1949-1951 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 12)
    - Anonymous threatening letters, 1954-1955 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 13)
    - Plittersdorf taxes (Stadtkasse), 1952-1963 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 14)
    - Plittersdorf repair records, 1955-1960 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - Property damage descriptions, Undated (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Property descriptions, furniture, rugs, etc., Undated (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Gutachten re: property -- Fleischmann, Kurt, 1955 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Gutachten re: property -- Kofferath, Josef, 1960 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - Gutachten re: property -- Nagel, Herbert (Kunsthistoriker), 1955-1956 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Gutachten re: property -- Seidenabel, K. F., 1956 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 21)
    - Gutachten re: property -- Strassberger, Jürgen (Gartenarchitekt), 1960 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 22)
    - Sale of property, Denglerstrasse, 1957-1959 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 23)
    - Sale of Rüngsdorf property, 1957 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 24)
  - Case files, Undated; 8.2
    - Background notes and materials re: restitution attempts, Undated (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 25)